Guide to the Social Ethics Pamphlet Collection
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Corporate Bodies, Series I
  - S
    - Southern Leaders Conference on Transportation, 1957 (Box 31, Folder 2)
      Subjects: African Americans; King, Martin Luther Jr. 1929-1968; Race relations; Southern States
      Comments: contains proceedings of the conference called by Martin Luther King, Jr., F.L. Shuttlesworth and C.K. Steel
    - Southern Newsletter, 1957-1958 (Box 31, Folder 3)
      Geographical location: Louisvillw, KY
      Comments: includes four issues
    - Southern Regional Council, 1946-1968 (Box 31, Folder 4)
      Subjects: Education; Labor movement; Race relations; Southern States
      Comments: includes papers and papmhlets concerning improvement of conditions in the South
    - Southern States Industrial Council, 1944, 1948 (Box 31, Folder 5)
      Comments: includes fundraising letter and anti-integration pamphlets
    - Southern Tenant Farmers Union, 1940-1941 (Box 31, Folder 6)
      Geographical location: Memphis, TN
      Subjects: Agriculture; Rural conditions; Southern States
      Comments: includes brief history and pamphlets on sharecroppers
    - Southwest Ecumenical Institute, 1958 (Box 31, Folder 7)
      Geographical location: Dallas, Tx
      Comments: contains booklet: The Church Faces the Commmunity
    - Soviet News, 1950 (Box 31, Folder 8)
      Geographical location: London, UK
      Subjects: Communism; Soviet Union
      Comments: contains Constitution of the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics
    - Soviet Russia Today, 1939 (Box 31, Folder 9)
      Subjects: Communism; Finland; Soviet Union
      Comments: contains booklet: The USSR and Finland, historical, economi, political facts and documents
    - Spanish Refugee Relief Campaign, 1936, 1939 (Box 31, Folder 10)
      Subjects: Spain-history-civil war, 1936-1939; International relief
      Comments: Contains two fundraising letters from campaign and one from the Peoples Committee of New Haven for the Labor Red Cross in Spain
    - Spiritual Mobilization, 1949-1959 (Box 31, Folder 11, 11a)
      Comments: contains 24 copies of Faith and Freedom (a journal of religion and capitalism), and other pro-business pamphlets
    - St. Labre Indian School (Box 30, Folder 16)
      Geographical location: Ashland, Montana
      Comments: Fundraising letter
    - St. Phillip's Episcopal Church, 1941, n.d. (Box 97, Folder 15)
      Subjects: Community organization; Religion and culture
      Comments: contains newsletter and a report about the church's work in Harlem
    - Standard Oil Company (New Jersey), 1945-1951 (Box 31, Folder 12)
      Geographical location: New York NY
      Subjects: Education; Labor movement
      Comments: contains pamphlets on industrial relations and an address about business and public education
    - Staple Cotton Cooperative Association, 1947 (Box 31, Folder 13)
      Geographical location: Greenwood, MI
      Comments: contains one issue of The Staple Cotton Review (1/47)
    - Statement on Religious Liberty in Relation to the 1960 Campaign (Box 31, Folder 14)
      Subjects: Religion and politics; United States--politics and government
      Comments: contains statement
    - Student Christian Association Movement, 1931, 1948 (Box 31, Folder 15)
      Subjects: Church work with students; College students; Religion and culture
      Comments: contains two pamphlets issued by SCM
    - Student Defenders of Democracy (Box 31, Folder 16)
      Subjects: College students; Religion and culture
      Comments: contains flyers on activities against nativist and facist movements
    - Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee, 1964 (Box 31, Folder 16a)
      Comments: contains papers about SNCC's Mississippi Summer Project
    - Students for Democratic Action (see Americans for Democratic Action, folder 42-2)
    - Summerfield Methodist Church, 1941-1947 (Box 99, Folder 16)
      Subjects: Church and social problems; Labor movement; New Haven; Race relations; Religion and culture
      Comments: contains papers and pamphlets about the church and the progressive activities of its pastor George Butler
    - Synagogue Council of America, 1943-1967 (Box 32, Folder 1)
      Subjects: Jews; Judaism; Religion and culture
      Comments: contains Labor Day message pamphlets (62-67) and booklet: Objectives of Goodwill
  - T
    - Tainan Theological College, 1959-1963 (Box 32, Folder 2)
      Geographical location: Tainan, Formosa
      Comments: contains newsletters from the college
    - Talladega College, 1961 (Box 32, Folder 3)
      Geographical location: Talladega, AL
      Subjects: African Americans; Education; Civil rights
      Comments: Contains newsletter and news release from faculty and staff in support of the freedom riders
    - Teachers Union, 1953 (Box 32, Folder 4)
      Subjects: Academic freedom
      Comments: contains newsletters and pamphlet on academic freedom
    - Technocratic Trendevents, 1938-1954 (Box 32, Folder 5)
      Subjects: Economic policy; Community organization
      Name changes etc.: Technocracy
      Comments: contains pamplets and monthly magazines issued by the group, which outline social and economic programs of the organization
    - Television Information Office, 1961 (Box 32, Folder 7)
      Comments: contains pamphlet: Television and the Pursuit of Excellence
    - Texas and Pacific Railway Company, 1953 (Box 32, Folder 8)
      Comments: contains letter and brochures from 1953 "Have Faith" advertising campaign
    - Textile Workers Union of America, 1955,1956 (Box 32, Folder 9)
      Comments: contains pamphlets on the history and goals of the union
    - Theological Education Fund, 1961 (Box 32, Folder 10)
      Comments: contains "Report on projects in Japan and Korea
    - Theological Education in America, 1955 (Box 32, Folder 11)
      Comments: contains: "Memorandum on the Theological Education of Negro Ministers"
    - Truth and Liberty Magazine, 1950 (Box 32, Folder 12)
      Geographical location: Minneapolis, MN
      Comments: contains 3 issues of the magazine
    - Tuition Plan, Inc., 1952 (Box 32, Folder 13)
      Comments: contains pamphlet: What are we when we're for education?
    - Twentieth Century Fund (Box 32, Folder 14)
      Comments: contains pamphlets on government policy on housing and electric power
  - U
    - U.S. Sponsoring Committee for Representation at the Congress of the Peoples for Peace, 1952 (Box 35, Folder 6)
      Subjects: Peace movements
      Comments: contains pamphlet on 1952 convention
    - UNICEF (see United Nations--UNICEF)
    - Ulysses S. Grant Scholarship Foundation, 1962 (Box 32, Folder 14a)
      Subjects: Education; New Haven; Race relations; Yale University
      Comments: contains pamphlet about a scholarship program run by the foundation for African American boys
    - Union Theological Seminary, 1951 (Box 32, Folder 16)
      Subjects: Cooperative societies; Religion and culture
      Comments: contains news release on communism in Asia and letter to Claremont Milk Cooperative
    - Union for Democratic Action, 1945 (Box 32, Folder 15)
      Subjects: Economic policy; United States--politics and government; Agriculture
      Comments: contains news release and position papers on the Full Employment Act of 1945; and pamphlet on subsidies to agriculture
    - Unitarian Fellowship for Social Justice, 1946 (Box 32, Folder 17)
      Geographical location: Dunkirk, NY
      Subjects: Religion and culture; Unitarians
      Comments: contains pamphlet: A Program for Social Action
    - Unitarian Service Committee (Box 32, Folder 18)
      Subjects: Unitarians International relief
      Comments: contains fundraising letter and pamphlet
    - United Auto Workers Union, 1947-1958 (Box 32, Folder 19)
      Comments: contians letters and pamphlets concerning union goals and activities; and information on the 1957 Kohler strike
    - United Cannery, Agricultural, Packing and Allied Workers of America, 1942 (Box 32, Folder 20)
      Comments: contains statement: The "Food For Victory" program and the peaceable settlement of agricultural labor disputes
    - United China Relief, Inc., 1942 (Box 33, Folder 1)
      Subjects: China; International relief; World War, 1939-1945
    - United Christian Council for Democracy, 1943-1946 (Box 33, Folder 2)
      Subjects: Religion and culture; Religion and politics
      Comments: contains newsletters and action alerts issued by the council
    - United Christian Youth Movement, 1944 (Box 33, Folder 4)
      Subjects: Juvenile delinquency; Youth
      Comments: contains paper on juvenile delinquency
    - United Church of Christ--Board for Homeland Ministries, 1961-1962, 1967 (Box 33, Folder 5, 8)
      Subjects: Church and social problems; Race relations; Religion and culture; Religion and international affairs; United Church of Christ
      Comments: contains reprints of sermons and articles published in the "Christian Preaching Fromn Unexepcted Pulpits" series; 6 issues of "The Journal"
    - United Churchwomen of Georgia--United Churchwomen of Atlanta, 1957 (Box 33, Folder 11)
      Comments: contains pronouncement made on race relations and the law
    - United Committee of South Slavic Americans, 1944-1946 (Box 33, Folder 12)
      Subjects: Yugoslavia; World war, 1939-1945
      Comments: contains newsletters amd pamphlets on the situation in Yugoslavia during and immediately following the war
    - United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America, 1959-1967 (Box 34, Folder 1)
      Comments: contains pamphlets on union's campaign on race relations
    - United Illuminating Company, 1949 (Box 34, Folder 2)
      Comments: conatains newsletter about company's opposition to the Tennessee Valley Authority (TVA)
    - United Lutheran Church in America--Board of Social Missions, 1954-1961 (Box 104)
      Subjects: Church and social problems; Lutherans; City missions;Race relations; Religion and culture
      Comments: contains extended collection of the Social Missions Quarterly
    - United Nations Appeal for Children (see American Overseas Aid--United Nations Appeal for Children)
    - United Nations Atomic Commisssion, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 3)
      Subjects: International organization; Nuclear disarmament
      Comments: contains resolution constituting commission
    - United Nations Food and Agriculture Organization, Geneva, Switzerland (Box 99, Folder 19)
      Geographical location: 1947-1949
      Subjects: Agriculture; International organization; International relief
      Comments: contains papers and pamphlets issued by the organization about the post-war food supply
    - United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration (Box 34, Folder 6)
      Subjects: International organization; International relief
      Comments: contains pamphlets with history of organization and letter listing other pamphlets issued by it
    - United Nations--Economic and Social Council--United States Delegation, 1949 (Box 99, Folder 17)
      Comments: contains reports from the delegation from the 9th session of the council
    - United Nations--Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO), 1946-1947 (Box 99, Folder 18)
      Comments: contains papers about the organization of the body and its initial programs
    - United Nations--High Commissioner for Refugees, 1957-1963 (Box 34, Folder 3)
      Subjects: Refugees; International organization
      Comments: contains report and pamphlets on the history of the organization
    - United Nations--Newsletter, 1948-1949 (Box 99, Folder 20)
      Subjects: International organization; International relations
      Comments: contains newsletters about the activities of the specialized agencies
    - United Nations--UNICEF, 1947 (Box 34, Folder 5)
      Comments: contains agency's 1946 report
    - United Negro College Fund, Inc. (Box 34, Folder 7)
      Comments: contains fundraising pamphlets
    - United Packinghouse Workers of America, 1945, 1948 (Box 34, Folder 8)
      Subjects: Labor Movement; Race relations; Religion and culture
      Comments: contains two position papers on race relations in the union, a Labor day address on religion and labor and a letter to workers during the 1948 strike
    - United Presbyterian Church in the United States of America--Board of Christian Education, 1958-1960 (Box 34, Folder 9)
      Subjects: Presbyterians; Religion and culture; Religion and politics
      Comments: contains two issues of Social Progress and working paper on ministry for families
    - United Presbyterian Church in the United States of America--Synod of Pennsylvania--Department of City and Industry, 1959 (Box 34, Folder 10)
      Geographical location: Harrisburg, PA
      Subjects: Church and social problems; Presbyterians; Race relations; Religion and culture
      Comments: contains paper on race relations in the church
    - United Republicans of America, 1965 (Box 34, Folder 11)
      Subjects: United States--politics and government
      Comments: conatains fundraisng letter and pamphlets
    - United States Catholic Conference--Social Action Department, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 12)
      Subjects: Catholic Church; Church and social problems; Race relations; Religion and culture
      Comments: contains 1967 Labor Day Statement
    - United States Department of Labor--Children's Bureau, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 13)
      Subjects: Child care; Migrant labor
      Comments: contains newsletter: Migrants' children need daytime care
    - United States National Commission for UNESCO, 1947,1954 (Box 34, Folder 14)
      Comments: contains materials on the 1955 Human Rights Day observance and the 1947 regional conference held in Denver, CO
    - United States National Student Association, 1950 (Box 34, Folder 15)
      Subjects: College students; Race relations
      Comments: contains pamphlet: "Human Relations in the Educational Community"
    - United States Steel Corporation, 1952, 1957 (Box 34, Folder 16)
      Comments: contains two statement of company officials before regulatory boards
    - United Steelworkers of America, 1944-1962 (Box 34, Folder 17)
      Geographical location: Pittsburgh, PA
      Comments: contains pamphlets and papers on the history and programs of the union
    - United Stewardship Council, 1945-1947 (Box 34, Folder 18)
      Geographical location: Hillsdale, MI
      Subjects: Ecumenical organization
      Comments: contains pamphlets on the program of the council
    - United Student Christian Council, 1956 (Box 34, Folder 19)
      Subjects: Church work with students; College students
      Comments: two pamphlets on the formation and program of the council
    - United Temperance Society of Connecticut, Inc., 1943, 1954 (Box 34, Folder 20)
      Comments: contains pamphlets and papers about the organization
    - United World Federalists, Inc., 1947-1953 (Box 34, Folder 21)
      Comments: contains newsletters, manifesto and solicitations
    - University Institute for Fundamental Training in Industry (Box 34, Folder 22)
      Geographical location: Rotterdam, Netherlands
      Comments: contains bulletin of education program on church and society
    - University of Chicago--Round Table, 1941, 1947 (Box 34, Folder 24)
      Subjects: Antisemitism; Education; Race relations
      Comments: contains issues of public issues journal Round Table: Anti-semitism, a threat to American unity? and Equality of educational opportunity
    - University of Chicago--School of Medicine and Federated Theological Faculty--Lilly Kokomo Project (Box 34, Folder 23)
      Subjects: Mental health; Religion and culture
      Comments: contains booklet: The Role of the Clergymen in Mental Health
    - University of Michigan, 1961 (Box 99, Folder 21)
      Comments: contains research report about public interest and health care
    - University of Missouri -- College of Agriculture, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 25)
      Subjects: Religion and culture; Rural conditions
      Comments: contains five part research series: The Church in Rural Missouri
    - University of the State of New York, 1950 (Box 35, Folder 1)
      Comments: contains report on equality of opportunity in the New York state college system
    - Urban Housing Management Association, Inc., 1945 (Box 35, Folder 2)
      Subjects: Community organization
      Comments: contains pamphlet outlining housing management program in Harlem, NY.
    - Urban League of Greater New Haven, 1961-1964 (Box 35, Folder 3)
      Subjects: African Americans; Community organization; New Haven
      Comments: The League was organized to address the social and economic situation of the Black population in the city. File contains papers about programs (housing, educational, vocational) run by the league
    - Urban League of Greater New York, 1945-1946 (Box 35, Folder 4)
      Subjects: African Americans; Community organization; Race relations
      Comments: The League was organized to address the social and economic situation of the Black population in the city. The file contains newsletters and reports on the League's activities.
    - Urban League of Pittsburgh, 1950-1957 (Box 14)
      Comments: The League was organized to address the social and economic situation of the Black population in the city. File contains newsletters and 1953 annual report.
  - V
    - Vanderbilt University--School of Religion--Foundation for the Study of Christianity and Democracy, 1950 (Box 15, Folder 19)
      Subjects: Religion and politics
      Comments: Contains "Democracy and the Christian faith," by Samuel Enoch Stumpf (April 18, 1950).
    - Visiting Nurse Association, 1954 (Box 35, Folder 7)
      Comments: contains 50th anniversary pamphlet
    - Voice of Healing, Inc., 1957 (Box 35, Folder 8)
      Geographical location: Dallas, TX
      Name changes etc.: AKA Last Day Sign-Gift Ministries
      Comments: contains issue of groups mission magazine
    - Voluntary Alcohol Control, 1944 (Box 35, Folder 9)
      Comments: contains papers and pamphlets issued by this sobriety movement
    - Volunteers of America, 1945-1946 (Box 35, Folder 10)
      Comments: contains letter to Dean Pope and a fiftieth anniversary pamphlet
  - W
    - War Resisters League, 1941-1942 (Box 35, Folder 12)
      Comments: contains pamphlets and booklet about pacifism in the second world war
    - Washington Federation of Churches, 1954 (Box 35, Folder 13)
      Subjects: Ecumenical organization; Race relations
      Comments: cotains pamphlet: An Approach Toward a Racially Inclusive Church
    - Watch Tower Bible and Tract Society, 1941-1953 (Box 35, Folder 14)
      Comments: contains tracts issued by the organization about Jehovah's Witnesses
    - Westinghouse Electric Corporation, 1945-1946 (Box 35, Folder 15)
      Comments: contains company statement on 1946 CIO strike and pamphlet commenting on American economic policy
    - White Citizens Council of Arkansas, 1955 (Box 35, Folder 16)
      Geographical location: Crossett, AK
      Comments: contains issue of "Arkansas Faith", a segregationist magazine
    - White House Conference on Children in Democracy--Citizen's Committee (Box 99, Folder 22)
      Subjects: Children
      Comments: contains bibliography and study outline issued by the committee on the status of children and programs geared toward them in American society
    - White House Conference on Education, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 17)
      Comments: contains pamphlet on education and industry
    - Why?: An Anarchist Bulletin, 1947 (Box 35, Folder 18)
      Comments: contains issue of newsletter
    - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom, 1932-1944 (Box 35, Folder 19)
      Subjects: Peace movements Women
      Comments: contains pamphlets about world peace
    - Woodrow Wilson Foundation, 1943-1946 (Box 35, Folder 20)
      Comments: contains pamphlets on post-war reconstruction
    - Work's Progress Administration, 1937 (Box 35, Folder 28)
      Comments: contains two surveys done by the WPA
    - Workers Defense League, 1936-1948 (Box 35, Folder 21-23)
      Comments: contains papers and pamphlets from organization which worked for legal, judicial and legislative rights of workers, incl. re. Odell Walker case (Virginia sharecropper) and issues of The Bulletin
    - Workers Education Association, 1939-1941 (Box 35, Folder 24)
      Geographical location: Tororto, Canada
      Comments: contains Trade unionist's handbook, newsletter "Labor News" and research bulletin on demographics of trade unions in Canada
    - Workers Education Bureau of America, 1949 (Box 35, Folder 25)
      Comments: contains one issue of Bureau's newletter
    - Workers Library Publishers, Inc., 1939, 1943 (Box 35, Folder 26)
      Subjects: Antisemitism; Labor movement
      Comments: contains pamphlet on antisemitism and labor songbook
    - Workers of the Common Life, 1949 (Box 35, Folder 27)
      Geographical location: Roxbury Crossing, MA
      Comments: contains newsletters from urban mission in Roxbury
    - World Alliance for International Friendship Through the Churches, 1941-1945 (Box 36, Folder 1)
      Subjects: Ecumenical movement; International organization; Religion and culture
      Name changes etc.: See also: Christian Conference on War and Peace
      Comments: contains pamphlets outlining the program of the Alliance
    - World Alliance of Reformed Churches, 1955 (Box 36, Folder 2)
      Comments: contains newsletter about religious conditions in the Soviet Union
    - World Alliance of YMCA's, 1949-1956 (Box 37, Folder 5)
      Name changes etc.: formerly World's Committee of YMCA's
      Comments: contains issues of "World Communique", report on Y activities in Africa and 1950 plenary meeting in Denmark
    - World Alliance of Youth, 1962 (Box 106, Folder 1)
      Comments: contains several issues of the Alliance's magazine the Way Review
    - World Committee for Christian Broadcasting, 1959 (Box 36, Folder 3)
      Comments: contains an issue of The Christian Broadcaster
    - World Committee for a World Constitutional Convention, 1960 (Box 36, Folder 4)
      Geographical location: Denver, CO
      Comments: contains letter of invitation to covention of World Federalists
    - World Conference of Pentecostal Churches, 1959-1960 (Box 36, Folder 5)
      Subjects: Pentecostals
      Comments: contains newsclipping and letters about David J. Du Plessis
    - World Council of Christian Eduation and Sunday School Association, 1955 (Box 36, Folder 6)
      Comments: contains issue of World Christian Education magazine
    - World Council of Churches, 1949-1963 (Box 36, Folder 7,7a,7b)
      Subjects: Ecumenical movement; Religion and culture; Refugees; Religion and international affairs
      Comments: contains Council newsletter on: ecumenical conferences; church and society issues; evangelism and newspaper clippings from the 1956 conference in Australia, papers on war refugees
    - World Council of Peace, 1951 (Box 36, Folder 8)
      Comments: contains an issue of the Council's bulletin
    - World Federation of Democratic Youth, 1945,1947 (Box 36, Folder 9)
      Subjects: Youth
      Comments: contains constitution,program,papers and pamphlets from 1947 world conference in Prague
    - World Health Organization, 1949-1955 (Box 99, Folder 23)
      Subjects: International organization; Medical care
      Comments: contains pamphlet describng the organization and its activities and several issues of the organizations newsletter
    - World Law Fund, 1966 (Box 36, Folder 10)
      Subjects: International relations; Nuclear disarmament
      Comments: contains booklet on disarmament
    - World Population Emergency Campaign, 1961, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 11)
      Comments: contains newsletter and fundraising pamphlets
    - World Student Service Fund, 1939-1943 (Box 36, Folder 12)